Kushal Nitin Jain

™ knjain1999@gmail.com

+4915234999483

Am Walperloh 29,98574, Schmalkalden, Germany

in Kushallain/LinkedIn

Kushaljain/Github



Profile

I am a masters student and a software developer with 1.5+ years of experience. I have worked on many projects and achieved results with the skillset listed below. I am looking for a challenging opportunity to showcase my skills and, at the same time, learn from your organization.

Professional Experience

Work student,

08/2023 - 11/2023 | Ilmenau, Germany

Institute for Microelectronics and Mechatronics Systems 🛮

- Demonstrated expertise in researching and developing 2 base designs for MEMS Gyroscope sensors.
- Developed a computing tool using Python to perform scientific calculations and in depth analysis of the product under development.
- Implemented Python Scripts to auto-generated 2D designs of multiple iterations, thus increasing efficiency by 50%.
- Focus area: Research work, Python, MEMS technology, Git, MS-office.

Software development Intern, Nitech Engineers Pvt. Ltd.

01/2022 - 08/2022 | Pune, India

- Collaborated on three projects, delivering impactful frontend solutions. Leveraged React.js framework to craft responsive and interactive user interfaces, ensuring optimal user experiences.
- Direct Client Interaction: Played a pivotal role in engaging directly with clients, contributing to project success and ensuring 100% client satisfaction.
- Demonstrated self-motivation, high self-organization and creative problem solving skills for independent project handling.
- Key Technologies:React.js, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Vite, React Router Dom, HTML5, CSS3, Materail UI, Git

Design Engineer(Intern + full time), KION group AG

01/2021 - 12/2021 | Frannkfurt, Germany

- My role here was design of the mechanical aspects of material handling system projects, to a given specification, within cost and time scale constraints, and to the customers' requirement.
- After training I worked on one project for Amazon warehouse in Madrid, Spain.
- I created layout drawings, customer approval drawings, Bill of material(BoM) and support during commissioning.

Projects

Adapt, (Freelaner) 11/2023

- Collaborated with the founders of a young start-up to develop a web application for users to book doctor consultation appointments.
- Designed multiple page responsive website having features like landing page, login-sign up page and portfolio page for all doctors registered with the start-up.
- Tech stack: React.js, JavaScript, Figma, Git, Notion
- https://adaptwellness.in/ ☑

OZO CRYPTO PLATFORM, (Freelancer)

01/2023

- Developed a crypto investment platform using React.js.
- Led a dedicated team of two members tasked with working in the frontend engineering and designing User Interface(UI) and also one admin panel with support after launch for 3 months.
- https://ozo-crypto.vercel.app/ ☑

XY Pen Plotter, (Master's curriculum project)

- Created XY Pen plotter using V-model approach.
- Engineered versatile mechatronics via 3D printing and electrical circuitry and designing, assembling and programming the ESP32 with Arduino IDE for high precision drawings.

Education

Masters in Mechatronics,

10/2022 - present | Germany

Schmalkalden University of Applied Sciences

08/2017 - 06/2021 | India

Bachelors of Technology, Pune University

Languages

Englsih

(Full working proficiency)

Hindi

(Native language)

Interests

Trekking | Networking | History | Cooking

German

(Limited working proficency-B1 level)